<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.9.1" xml:lang="en-US">
  <compounddef id="indexpage" kind="page">
    <compoundname>index</compoundname>
    <title>AMD Device Library eXtra</title>
    <briefdescription>
    </briefdescription>
    <detaileddescription>
<para><heading level="2">ADLX Developer Documentation </heading>
</para>
<para>AMD Device Library eXtra (ADLX) is AMD&apos;s application programming interface (API) library for Microsoft Windows® based driver configuration. The ADLX API is a programming interface designed to allow software applications communicate directly with AMD hardware and access their resources.<linebreak/>
</para>
<para>This document includes detailed information on the API&apos;s programming interfaces, helpers, functions, types, as well as code samples and usage scenarios to help developers get started. The document also includes information on system requirements, bindings development, and advanced configurations to help developers overcome common issues when integrating the API.<linebreak/>
<linebreak/>
</para>
<para><heading level="2">ADLX Programming Guide </heading>
</para>
<para><ref refid="page_adlxprogrammingguide" kindref="compound">ADLX Programming Guide</ref> contains information for developers to get started, such as hardware and software requirements, the minimum-supported operating system versions, and a Quick Start guide with instructions on how to build applications in each of the supported programming languages.<linebreak/>
<linebreak/>
</para>
<para><heading level="2">ADLX Samples </heading>
</para>
<para><ref refid="domain_sample_page" kindref="compound">ADLX Samples</ref> provides code samples in C, C++, C#, Java, and Python to demonstrate ADLX functionality usage scenarios in basic applications to help developers get started quickly.<linebreak/>
<linebreak/>
</para>
<para><heading level="2">ADLX SDK References </heading>
</para>
<para><ref refid="page_sdk" kindref="compound">ADLX SDK References</ref> provides descriptions for all ADLX programming aspects such as helpers, functions, interfaces (with their respective methods) and ADLX data types.<linebreak/>
<linebreak/>
<linebreak/>
</para>
<para>For more information on AMD Graphics and related SDKs, visit <ulink url="https://gpuopen.com/adlx/">AMD GPUOpen</ulink>. </para>
    </detaileddescription>
    <location file="D:/AMD_Git/adlx_release/drivers/ADLX/docs/Config/ADLXDox.h"/>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
